GENERAL APPLICANTS' INFORMATION



ChM. Dr. KHAIRUL ADLI BIN NIKMAN

An active, creative and multi skill professional. Has more than 10 years of experience in forensic analysis, instrumentation, laboratory management and forensic medicine. Has the ability to lead and committed for best results.

merahberapi@gmail.com; khairuladli@moh.gov.my 7 019-7749921



Address No. 120, Jalan Jati 1/3, Jati Park, Putra Nilai

71800 Nilai, Negeri Sembilan

Occupation Forensic Scientific Officer (Grade C44)

(Registered Chemist with Institut Kimia Malaysia)

Kementerian Kesihatan Malaysia **Employer** Department of Forensic Medicine,

Hospital Sungai Buloh

Head of Forensic Medicine Laboratory Responsibility

Personal Information

Age : 41 Date of Birth : 9 February 1980

Race : Malay Religion : Islam

Nationality : Malaysian Sex : Male

Marital : Married **Mykad No.** : 800209-06-5071

Status

Wife's Name : Nur Azilah Binti Abdullah

Children : 3

Adni Safiya Binti Khairul Adli

Idham Harith Bin Khairul Adli

Adni Khairina Binti Khairul Adli

Language : Excellent in spoken and written Bahasa Malaysia and good in English.

Has a minimum proficiency in Arabic.

Hobby : Read novels and comics, and write Malay poem, articles, short stories

and books.

Employment History

April 2009 – Present : Forensic Scientific Officer

Department of Forensic Medicine,

Sungai Buloh Hospital

- Head of Laboratory, Forensic Medicine Laboratory, Forensic Medicine Department,

Hospital Sg. Buloh, Selangor.

February 2007 – April

2009

Forensic Scientific Officer

Institute of Forensic Medicine,

Kuala Lumpur Hospital

Kuala Lumpur

September 2004 January 2007 **Forensic Scientific Officer**

Department of Forensic Medicine,

Sultanah Aminah Hospital

Johor Bahru

1997 - August 2004

Part-time worker at cafeteria of Kompleks Pejabat Kerajaan Negeri Pahang, Daerah Jerantut. (Worked during study break and semester break from 1998 - 2004).

Part-time worker (as a store keeper) at QMA Emporium in Jerantut, Pahang for one month in 1999.

Part-time worker at my uncle's workshop (motorcycle) at Kampung Kuala Triang, Bera, Pahang for one month in

1997.

Education Background

UPSR - 4A

Universiti Sains Islam Malaysia 2013 - 2018Doctor of Philosophy (Science & Technology) Research & Thesis: Production, Characterization and Application of Activated Carbon from Cocoa Nib Wastes 2009 - 2011**Universiti Malaya** Master of Science (Analytical Chemistry & Instrumental Analysis) CGPA: 3.25 2000 - 2004**Universiti Sains Malaysia** Bachelor of Science (Forensic Science) CGPA: 3.10 1998 - 2000**Universiti Sains Malaysia** Matriculation - passed Sekolah Menengah Agama Persekutuan, Jalan Labu, Seremban, 1992 – 1997 Negeri Sembilan SPM – Grade 1 with aggregate 11 PMR - 8A 1B 1987 - 1991 Sekolah Kebangsaan Bandar Pusat Jengka, Maran, Pahang

Experience Profiles

Forensic Scientific Officer (Grade C44)

 Department of Forensic Medicine, Sungai Buloh Hospital Sungai Buloh, Selangor

Head of Forensic Medicine Laboratory, Hospital Sungai Buloh (since 2017).

Interviewer (Technical) for Bahagian Pengurusan Latihan and Bahagian Sains Kesihatan Bersekutu for Hadiah Latihan Persekutuan - (2021)

Deputy Head of Selangor's Allied Health Professionals (2020 – 2021)

Head of Selangor's Forensic Science Officers (2020 – 2021)

PRO TEM Member of Majlis Profesion Kesihatan Bersekutu Malaysia (MPKBM) (since April 2019).

Head of Profession for Forensic Science Officer in Ministry of Health (1 June 2017 – 31 May 2019).

Prepared, presented and submitted the National Forensic Science Officer's Strategic Plan (2019 – 2023) to Bahagian Sains Kesihatan Bersekutu, KKM.

Interviewer (Technical) with JPA for Science Officer (Forensics) post (2019).

Alternate members of the National Technical Committee on Forensic Sciences (since 2017).

Standard Technical Committee Member for Analytical Chemistry NOSS Level 4 and 5 (2016).

Standard Evaluation Technical Committee Member for Analytical Chemistry NOSS Level 4 and 5 (2016).

Expert Panel for National Occupational Skills Standard (NOSS) for Analytical Chemistry - Level 5 (Malaysia Skills Advanced Diploma) (2016).

Expert Panel in Preparation of National Guideline in Management of Methanol Poisoning Outbreak (2013 and 2018).

Writer for MyHEALTH Portal (KKM) (<u>www.myhealth.gov.my</u>) (Since 2012).

A committee member in preparing the paperwork for Forensic Toxicology Laboratory for Institute of Forensic Medicine, Hospital Kuala Lumpur (2007).

Research/Dissertation/Thesis

Thesis:

'Production, Characterization and Applications of Activated Carbon from Cocoa (*Theobroma cacao*) Nibs Waste'

Universiti Sains Islam Malaysia and Malaysian Cocoa Board, 2018

Supervisor: Associate Professor Dr. Mohd Sukri Hassan

Dissertation:

'Determination of Alcohol in Postmortem Blood in Jabatan Perubatan Forensik, Hospital Sungai Buloh'

Universiti Malaya and Forensic Medicine Laboratory, Department of Forensic Medicine, Sungai Buloh Hospital, 2011

Supervisor: Professor Chuah Cheng Hock

'Determination of Nicotine Concentration in Selected Cigarettes'

Universiti Sains Malaysia, 2004

Supervisor: Dr. Rafiquzzaman, School of Health Science

Research:

'Methanol Poisoning - Laboratory Findings: A Review'

Research ID: 30033. NMRR ID: NMRR-16-2881-30033.

'Delayed death in methanol intoxication: An autopsy case report'

Research ID: 45528. NMRR ID: NMRR-18-3478-45528. Collaboration study with Faculty of Medicine, UiTM Sungai Buloh.

'Prevalence of Postmortem Blood Alcohol Concentration Among Deaths in Hospital Sungai Buloh During 2017'

Research ID: 42855. NMRR ID: NMRR-18-1658-42855.

Presented during National Conference on Forensic Medicine & Science (NCFMS 2018), Putrajaya.

'Determination of Methanol and Ethanol in Biological Specimens by Headspace Gas Chromatography - A Review'

Research ID: 44977. NMRR ID: NMRR-18-3403-44977. On-going study.

'Removal of Paracetamol using Cocoa Nib Activated Carbon'

Universiti Sains Islam Malaysia and Malaysia Cocoa Board, Bandar Baru Nilai, 2017 Supervisor: Dr. Sukri Hassan (USIM), Dr. Fisal Ahmad (Malaysian Cocoa Board), Dr. Mohd Azmier Ahmad (USM, Transkerian) & Dr Che Wan Zanariah (USIM)

'Analysing Cocoa Nib Activated Carbon Using Principal Component Analysis' Universiti Sains Islam Malaysia and Malaysia Cocoa Board, Bandar Baru Nilai, 2017 Supervisor: Dr. Sukri Hassan (USIM), Dr. Fisal Ahmad (Malaysian Cocoa Board), Dr. Mohd Azmier Ahmad (USM, Transkerian) & Dr Che Wan Zanariah (USIM)

'The Effects of Physicochemical Activation, on Porosity and Surface Functional Groups'

Universiti Sains Islam Malaysia and Malaysia Cocoa Board, Bandar Baru Nilai, 2016 Supervisor: Dr. Sukri Hassan (USIM), Dr. Fisal Ahmad (Malaysian Cocoa Board), Dr. Mohd Azmier Ahmad (USM, Transkerian) & Dr Che Wan Zanariah (USIM)

'The Adsorption Capacity of Physicochemically Prepared Activated Carbon from Cocoa Nibs on Methylene Blue'

Universiti Sains Islam Malaysia and Malaysia Cocoa Board, Bandar Baru Nilai, 2016 Supervisor: Dr. Sukri Hassan (USIM), Dr. Fisal Ahmad (Malaysian Cocoa Board), Dr. Mohd Azmier Ahmad (USM, Transkerian) & Dr Che Wan Zanariah (USIM) Presented during Academic International Dalog Conference 2016, Open University, Seremban.

'Preparation of Activated Carbon from Cocoa Nibs Waste Using Chemical Activation Technique'

Universiti Sains Islam Malaysia and Malaysia Cocoa Board, Bandar Baru Nilai, 2016 Supervisor: Dr. Sukri Hassan (USIM), Dr. Fisal Ahmad (Malaysian Cocoa Board), Dr. Mohd Azmier Ahmad (USM, Transkerian) & Dr Che Wan Zanariah (USIM)

'Substance Intoxication – An Instant Remedy from Cocoa'

Universiti Sains Islam Malaysia and Malaysia Cocoa Board, Bandar Baru Nilai, 2016 Supervisor: Dr. Sukri Hassan (USIM), Dr. Fisal Ahmad (Malaysian Cocoa Board), Dr. Mohd Azmier Ahmad (USM, Transkerian) & Dr Che Wan Zanariah (USIM) Presented during Allied Health Scientific Conference 2016, Kuala Lumpur.

Publication

'Methanol poisoning in Klang Valley, Malaysia: Autopsy case series'

Forensic Science International Report, 3(Supplement 2):100170, Jan. 2021

'Removal of methylene blue from aqueous solution using cocoa (Theobroma cacao) nib-based activated carbon treated with hydrochloric acid'

Malaysian Journal of Fundamental and Applied Sciences. Vol. 14, No. 2 (2018) 193-197.

'Adsorption Capacity of Chemically Prepared Cocoa nibs based Activated Carbon on Methylene blue'

International Journal of Petrochemistry and Research – 10 April 2017 Int. J Pet Res. 2017; 1(1): 15-18.

'Blood Alcohol Analysis For Postmortem Blood Samples Received In Department of Forensic Medicine, Sungai Buloh Hospital'

The Journal of HSB, Vol. 1, No. 1 (2013).

'Turn Around Time (TAT) for Medico-legal Specimens in the Department of Forensic Medicine, Kuala Lumpur, 2006'

Kuala Lumpur Hospital Journal of Quality Improvement, Vol 10 No. 2 (2007).

Other Publication

Book:

Membongkar Konspirasi Zion Zionis

ISBN: 978-967-5391-75-0 Hijjaz Records Publishing

2018

Magazine:

Daun Betik Merawat Kanser

Dewan Kosmik (DBP) Januari 2018

Minyak Pati Serai Antikanser

Dewan Kosmik (DBP) Disember 2017

Peralatan Automasi Dalam Analisis Cap Jari

Dewan Kosmik (DBP) Ogos 2017

Potensi Antioksidan Koko

Dewan Kosmik (DBP) Julai 2017

Kunyit Rempah Sepanjang Zaman

Dewan Kosmik (DBP) April 2017

Khasiat Daun Kari Pelbagai

Dewan Kosmik (DBP) Februari 2017

Pandan Anti Bakteria

Dewan Kosmik (DBP) Januari 2017

Daun Kesum Antikanser

Dewan Kosmik (DBP) Julai 2016

Buah Letup-letup Antibakteria

Dewan Kosmik (DBP) Oktober 2015

Sirih Tumbuhan Ajaib

Dewan Kosmik (DBP) Mei 2015

Online Portal (MyHEALTH)

Trends, Challenges and Strategies in Forensic Science

19 Mei 2015; http://www.myhealth.gov.my/tren-cabaran-dan-strategi-dalam-bidang-forensik/

Pernahkah Anda Menemui Mayat?

8 Sept 2015; http://www.myhealth.gov.my/pernahkah-anda- menemui-mayat/

Kerana Arak Badan Binasa

7 Jan 2014; http://www.myhealth.gov.my/kerana-arak-badan-binasa/

DNA dan Forensic Science

7 Jan 2014; http://www.myhealth.gov.my/dna-dan-sains-forensik/

DNA - Suatu Kepastian

7 Jan 2014; http://www.myhealth.gov.my/dna-suatu-kepastian/

CSI – Antara Drama dan Realiti

7 Jan 2014; http://www.myhealth.gov.my/csi-antara-drama-dan-realiti/

Aku Bebas

7 Jan 2014; http://www.myhealth.gov.my/aku-bebas/

Keperluan dan Kepentingan Postmortem Serta Pandangan Dari Sudut Agama

5 Oct 2011; http://www.myhealth.gov.my/v2/index.php/my/umum/forensik/peranan-perubatan-forensik-di-kkm

Awards

Bronze Medal in Seoul International Invention Fair 2016 – Cocoa Nibs (Theobroma cacao) Based Activated Carbon.

Anugerah Perkhidmatan Cemerlang (APC) Perkhidmatan Awam Tahun 2011.

Professional Training

- 1. Certificate of Training on MS ISO 17025 (24 April 2019)
- 2. Demonstration and Practical Training on Surface Area & Porosity Analyzer Micromeritics ASAP 2020 (2016)
- 3. Demonstration and Practical Training on Rapid Extraction System SOXTHERM (2016)
- 4. Demonstration and Practical Training on Agilent 1260 Infinity Analytical-scale Fraction Collector (2016)
- 5. Demonstration and Practical Training on pH Meter Multiparameter SevenExcellence (Mettler Toledo) (2014)
- 6. Demonstration and Practical Training on Adsorption and Kinetic study by using Agilent Cary UV-Vis 60 (2014)
- 7. Demonstration and Practical Training on Vertical Dual Zone Split Tube Furnace with Quartz Tube (2014)
- 8. Demonstration and Practical Training on Agilent 630 FTIR (2014)
- Certificate of Training in Internal Auditing for OSH Management System: MS 1722:2011
 OHSAS 18001:2007 (18 October 2012)
- 10. Certificate of Attendance for training in Fundamental of Shimadzu UV-VIS Spectrophotometer (7 September 2012)
- 11. Certificate of Training on Waters HPLC on-site Training (22 April 2012)
- 12. Certificate of Training on Phox CO-Oximeter (26 February 2012)
- 13. Certificate of Training in Internal Auditing for Quality Management System: ISO 9001 : 2000 (11 November 2008)
- 14. Certificate of Training on Thermo-Scientific Gas Chromatography Mass Spectrometer On-site Training (2008)

Professional Membership

- 1. Member of Association of Scientific Officer in Ministry of Health (ASOMH).
- 2. Member in Forensic Science Society of Malaysia (FSSM).
- 3. Member of Institut Kimia Malaysia (IKM).

Referee

Associate Professor Dr Mohd Sukri B. Hassan

Senior Lecturer Fakulti Sains & Teknologi, Universiti Sains Islam Malaysia 012-648 1670 mohdsukri@usim.edu.my

Associate Professor Dr Ahmad Fahmi Lim B. Abdullah

Senior Lecturer Pusat Pengajian Sains Kesihatan, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian 012-750 7093 fahmilim@usm.my

Dr Razuin Bt. Rahimi

Senior Lecturer
Centre for Pathology Diagnostic & Research, Laboratories, Faculty of Medicine,
Universiti Teknologi MARA, Selangor
012-965 2145
razuin@gmail.com

Dr Fisal Ahmad

Senior Research Officer Malaysian Cocoa Board, Cocoa Innovative Technology Centre (CITC), Nilai 012-965 2145 fisalcocoa@gmail.com